I feel bad that I've done a lot of
talking and a lot less coding in this
section, but I did realize that I do
have to show you just a couple more
things and that is I haven't shown you
how to read the documentation for an
API. So, um here under personality um is
the advice slip API that we were using.
So, you can click on this link and it'll
take you to advice slip and it says um
your advice is cached for 2 seconds. any
repeat request within two seconds will
return the same piece of advice, which
was actually very helpful for teaching
because I needed it to return the same
thing. So, you could see that both
functions did the same thing. Um, but
it'll tell you the HTTP method to
interact with it is a get request and if
you use this URL, then it will return
you a random piece of advice. Um, you
can actually pass in additional
parameters if you want. Um, if you want
to get a specific piece of advice, then
you can grab it by its ID. And what you
do is you make a get request to this URL
and then at the end where it says slip
ID, you insert it. So if you want to get
um advice number 99, then you'd say
https/api.advicelip.com/advice/99.
Um
searching advice um you would make a get
request to this URL and you would um
this URL right here. So it would be
advice slash search slash the thing
you're searching for. So if you're
searching and if it's found um it
returns an array of slip objects. So
rather than going into JSON data advice
or yeah JSON data advice, you would go
into
um you would go into JSON data and you
would loop through all of the advice
objects that it gives you back. Um,
and so you can see that, um, it
documents pretty well how to use this
API. Let's go look at another one. Um,
let's look at this. Chucknorris.io.
Hey, Chuck Norris.io. So, if we come
here, documentation will look a little
bit different, but to retrieve a random
Jo Chuck Norris joke in JSON format, you
would visit, you'd make a git request to
that URL. Um, if you want it in a given
category, you'd make a git request to
that URL and you'd put in category at
the end. If you want to retrieve a list
of all of the available categories, you
make a get request to that URL. Um, and
if you want to just use a free text
search, so search for a specific joke,
then you use a get request to that URL.
And so you can see it's a very well
documented how you would use this. And
so a helpful thing to do is just go
through and read the documentation for
how your API works or the one that
you're trying to